Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Township Records, 1820s-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Township Records
1820s-1996
Ann Arbor (Mich.: Township)
0472 Cb 2; CB outsize
Township record books, 1845-1902; registers of births, 1906-1943; registers of deaths, 1897-1912; poll books, tally sheets, and statement of votes from polls within township; records relating to surveys, repairs, etc. of township roads; reports and compiled statistics pertaining to township schools; property assessment roll books; and other miscellaneous records.
11 linear feet
100 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the township office (donor no. 9467 ) in May 2004.
The record group is open to research.
The records of Ann Arbor Township include township record books, 1845-1902; registers of births, 1906-1943; registers of deaths, 1897-1912; poll books, tally sheets, and statement of votes from polls within township; records relating to surveys, repairs, etc. of township roads; reports and compiled statistics pertaining to township schools; property assessment roll books; and other miscellaneous records. The records are organized into nine series:
Township Record Books, 1845-1902
Registers of Births, 1906-1943
Registers of Deaths, 1897-1912
Election records
Highway Records, 1820s-1920s
Treasurer's records, 1830s-1923
School Records, 1840s-1930s
Miscellaneous, 1827-1920s
Assessment Roll Books, 1872-1996
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.: Township); Elections--Michigan--Ann Arbor (Township); Ann Arbor (Mich.: Township)--Genealogy.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Ann Arbor (Township); Roads--Michigan--Ann Arbor (Township); Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor (Township); Taxation--Michigan--Ann Arbor (Township); Washtenaw County (Mich.)
- Township Record Books, 1845-1902
  Township Record Books includes minutes of annual and township board meetings. Also variously includes election results; motions and agreements; oaths of office; reports of Highway Commissioners' and minutes of the Board of Health.)
  - 1845-1858 (Box 1)
  - 1858-1889 (Box 1)
  - 1889-1902 (Box 1)
- Registers of Births, 1906-1943
  Registers of Births records babies born in (or registered) in the Ann Arbor township. Information in each entry includes place and date of birth; the infants name, sex, birth order, and legitimacy; the father's and mother's name, residence, race, age, birthplace, and occupation; as well as a certification of the attending physician or midwife and the date of registration.)
  - 1906-1914 (Box 1)
  - 1914-1919 (Box 1)
  - 1919-1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1943 (Box 1)
- Registers of Deaths, 1897-1912
  Registers of Deaths records deaths Ann Arbor township residents and other deaths that occurred in the township. Information includes place and date of death; the name of the deceased and often his sex, date of birth, age, marital status, age at marriage, number of children, birthplace, name of father, his birthplace, maiden name of mother, her birthplace, occupation of deceased and name of informant; as well as the cause of death, a certification of a physician or coroner, and the date of registration.)
  - 1897-1900 (Box 1)
  - 1900-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1905-1909 (Box 1)
  - 1909-1912 (Box 1)
  - 1912-1919 (Box 1)
  - 1919-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1925-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1943 (Box 1)
- Election records
  Election records include a variety of poll books, poll lists and voter registration books documenting the electoral process and election results in Ann Arbor Township.
  - Poll Books, Tally Sheets, And Statement Of Votes
    - 1892-1919 (Box 2)
    - 1920-1938, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Poll lists, 1830s-1920s (Box 4)
  - Voter Registration Book, 1882-1901 (Box 4)
  - Oaths Of Office; Acceptances, 1830s-1880s; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Official oaths, 1883-1885 (Box 4)
  - Official Bonds And Oaths Of Office, 1908-1942 (scattered); 12 volumes booklets (Box 5)
  - Election Returns; statement of votes, 1870s-1890s (Box 5)
  - Party Enrollment Books
    (Information includes date of enrollment, enrolled number, name, address, party affiliation and remarks. The 1906-1910 volume includes age, nativity, and race.)
    - 1906-1910 (Box 5)
    - 1912 (Box 5)
- Highway Records, 1820s-1920s
  Highway Records include proceedings of the Commissioners of Highways, descriptions of the highway districts, petitions and orders for road construction and repair, and road surveys.
  - Commissioners of Highways Record book, 1842-1889 (Box 5)
    (contains descriptions of road districts)
  - Proceedings of Commissioners of Highways, 1846-1877 (Box 5)
    (includes minutes of meetings)
  - Mixed records, 1820s-1920s (Box 5)
    (includes annual reports of the Commissioners of Highways, petitions and orders, road survey records; and road repair vouchers)
  - Record of roads, 2 volumes in 1 folder (Box 5)
    (arranged alphabetically by name; appears to be an index to a record book of work done on roads)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Treasurer's records, 1830s-1923
  - Account Books
    The Treasurer's records, arranged by type of fund; include accounts of contingent fund, highway fund, road repair fund, and school funds
    - 1850-1888 (Box 6)
    - 1891-1900 (Box 6)
    - 1901-1923 (Volume 1)
  - Audited account book, 1837-1845 (Box 6)
  - Audited accounts (Box 6)
  - Journeyman's book, 1830s-1840s (Box 6)
    (purpose uncertain)
- School Records, 1840s-1930s
  The School Records series, 1840s-1930s, files of the Board of School Inspectors annual statistical reports of school districts 1890s-1920s and miscellaneous reports.
  - Board of School Inspectors, 1883-1890 (Box 7)
  - Annual Statistical Report Of School Districts, ca., 1890s-1920s (Box 7)
  - Township Clerk's Annual Report Of School Districts, ca., 1910s-1920s (Box 7)
    (includes uniform annual statistics for each school district. Information includes student census; financial accounts; and number of graduates)
  - Miscellaneous School District Records, circa, 1840s-1930s (Box 8)
    (includes school orders and vouchers; apportionments for school districts; school inspectors reports; school district directors reports; and school census reports.)
- Miscellaneous, 1827-1920s
  The Miscellaneous records series a registry of Marks and Estrays, 1827-1834 (brands used to mark cattle and sheep); a Record of Strays (stray livestock and the damage they caused), Chattle Mortgage records, 1830s-1920s; and an assortment of petitions, meeting notices, and grand jury lists.
  - Marks And Estrays, 1827-1834; 1844 (Box 8)
    (includes drawings of marks (brands) for sheep and the name of the township resident registering the mark)
  - Township Record of Strays, 1845-1894 (Box 8)
    (includes notarized accounts of damages or costs incurred by stray sheep and cows; includes slight board of health material at end of volume)
  - Supervisors report of dogs in assessing district, 1918 (Box 8)
  - Methodist Episcopal Church miscellanea, 1845; 1852 (Box 8)
  - Ann Arbor Peech Yellows Record, 1891-1900 (Box 8)
    (includes a list of orchards examined and the percentage of trees affected by the disease)
  - Sparrow Bounty Book, 1909-1921 (Box 8)
    (includes receipts for bounties paid on sparrows)
  - Board of Health proceedings, 1877-1889 (Box 8)
  - List of potential jurors?? (Box 8)
  - Chattel Mortgages Book, 1889 (Volume 2)
    (Includes name of mortgagee and mortgagor and dates of the mortgage)
  - Chattel Mortgages Records, circa, 1830s-1920s (Box 9)
  - Various unprocessed records, including notices of meetings, sundry petitions, grand jury lists, contracts, etc. (Box 10)
  - Various unprocessed records, including notices of meetings, sundry petitions, grand jury lists, contracts, etc. (Box 11)
    continued
- Assessment Roll Books, 1872-1996; 98 volumes
  The Assessment Roll Books record real and personal property valuations from 1872 to 1996. Information includes name of owner; legal description of property; number of acres in parcel; value of parcel; value of personal estate; and amount of tax assessed for state, county, township, highway, and special purposes; volumes after 1960 were sampled on an every other year basis.
  - 1872-1887, 14 volumes
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 3)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 4)
      (continued)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 5)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 6)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 7)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 8)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 9)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 10)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 11)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 12)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 13)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 14)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 15)
    - 1872-1887 (Volume 16)
  - 1900-1960, 61 volumes
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 17)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 18)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 19)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 20)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 21)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 22)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 23)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 24)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 25)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 26)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 27)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 28)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 29)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 30)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 31)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 32)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 33)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 34)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 35)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 36)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 37)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 38)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 39)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 40)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 41)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 42)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 43)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 44)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 45)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 46)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 47)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 48)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 49)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 50)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 51)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 52)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 53)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 54)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 55)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 56)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 57)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 58)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 59)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 60)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 61)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 62)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 63)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 64)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 65)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 66)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 67)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 68)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 69)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 70)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 71)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 72)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 73)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 74)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 75)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 76)
    - 1900-1960 (Volume 77)
  - 1962, 2 volumes
    - 1962 (Volume 78)
    - 1962 (Volume 79)
  - 1964 (Volume 80)
  - 1966 (Volume 81)
  - 1968 (Volume 82)
  - 1970 (Volume 83)
  - 1972, 2 volumes
    - 1972 (Volume 84)
    - 1972 (Volume 85)
  - 1974 (Volume 86)
  - 1976, 2 volumes
    - 1976 (Volume 87)
    - 1976 (Volume 88)
  - 1978, 2 volumes
    - 1978 (Volume 89)
    - 1978 (Volume 90)
  - 1980, 2 volumes
    - 1980 (Volume 91)
    - 1980 (Volume 92)
  - 1982 (Volume 93)
  - 1984 (Volume 94)
  - 1986 (Volume 95)
  - 1988 (Volume 96)
  - 1990 (Volume 97)
  - 1992 (Volume 98)
  - 1994 (Volume 99)
  - 1996 (Volume 100)